Let's say you wanted to test a function that finds
假设要测试这样一个函数
the nearest perfect square less than or equal to a certain number.
找到小于等于且最接近某个数字的完美平方
Your first approach might be testing it
第一种方法可能是
interactively in a terminal or Jupyter notebook, like this.
在终端或 Jupyter Notebook 中以交互方式测试 就像这样
So first, we'll import the function from the file,
首先 从文件中导入函数
and now, we'll start testing it with different values.
现在 开始使用不同的值进行测试
So let's try five,
尝试一下 5
that should return four since that's the nearest perfect square less than or equal to it.
应该返回 4 因为其是小于等于且最接近 5 的完美平方
Let's try negative number,
试试负数
which should return zero, which does.
应该返回 0 结果也确实如此
Now, let's try an actual perfect square,
现在 尝试一个完美平方值
nine which should return nine,
9 应该返回 9
and let's just try another one,
再试一个
23 that returns 16.
23 返回 16
So awesome. While this does test the function,
不错! 这确实测试了函数的功能
it's still a poor way to test because it isn't repeatable,
但这仍然是一种糟糕的测试方式 因为其不可重复
requires you to type these in manually,
要求手动输入
and doesn't tell you whether it's returning the correct answers.
也并没有告诉你 返回的是否为正确答案
Imagine you have hundreds of functions you need to test
想象一下 你需要测试数百个函数
and test repeatedly while iterating on your project,
并且在迭代项目时反复测试
you can see how inefficient and unreliable of a method this approach would be for that.
可以看出这种方法对于上述情况来说 有多么低效和不可靠
After this, you may consider putting your test code into a file to make it repeatable,
这种方法之后 你可能会考虑将测试代码放入文件中 使其可重复
and end up writing this.
最后写出这些内容
This is better because your test code is now on a file that you
这样好一点 因为测试代码现在位于文件中
can run to repeat the same tests without much work,
可以重复运行相同的测试 不需要太多的工作
but it's still not telling you whether it's getting the right answers.
但它仍然没有告诉你是否得出了正确答案
You'd still have to check,
你还需要检查
five, the last one's four,
5 对应的结果 4
that's correct, negative 12, oh yeah,
这是正确的 -12 嗯对的
that's zero. Still pretty slow.
结果是 0 还是很慢
If we print the correct expected result with each answer,
如果我们在每次结果中打印出预期的正确答案
now, we do have a clear way to check out the results.
我们就有了更明确的方式来检查结果
However, we still need to check these results
但是仍然需要手动检查
manually to compare what they returned and the correct answer yourself.
对比函数返回的结果和预期的答案
This is not ideal if we're running a large amount of unit tests often.
如果需要经常进行大量的单元测试 这并不理想
We can use assert to ensure that each result is identical to the correct answer.
我们可以使用 assert 来确保每个结果与正确答案相同
This is much better since it checks our results automatically.
这样做要好得多 因为它会自动检查我们的结果
However, look what happens when something fails.
但是看看出现失败时会发生什么
Let's say, I didn't put this equal sign and I only put a less than sign.
比如说我没有用等号 只是放了一个小于符号
The result is messy and it stops the program.
结果显示很乱 并且会使程序停止运行
Ideally, running a test should run all the unit tests
理想情况下 测试应运行完所有单元测试
and let you know which ones failed and which ones succeeded.
让你知道哪些失败了 哪些成功了
This can't happen if it stops with every failure.
如果每次失败都会停止运行 就不是这样的情况了
Any tests that happened after this one failed,
在发生此次失败后的任何测试
we can't see the results of.
我们都看不到结果
In addition, the message where failure is messier than it needs to be.
另外 失败的信息太过混乱 很多内容并不需要
Fortunately, there are great tools available in
幸运的是 Python 有很棒的工具
Python that we will use to create effective unit tests.
可以用来创建有效的单元测试